Guide to the Stanford University, Management Development Program, Audiovisual Materials
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Management Development Program, audiovisual materials
1979-1992
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Management Development Program
SC0456
7 Linear Feet
Audio cassettes, 1981-1988, and video tapes, 1988-1992, of speakers and class discussions. Stanford administrators and faculty who spoke include Robert Street, Ray Bacchetti, Lowell Price, William Massy, John Ford, John Schwartz, Richard Lyman, Donald Kennedy, and Albert Hastorf. Also includes office files, 1979-1984, containing memoranda, correspondence, articles, class materials, text of talks, and other records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Administrative transfers, 1993, 1994.
Description of the Collection
Audio cassettes, 1981-1988, and video tapes, 1988-1992, of speakers and class discussions. Stanford administrators and faculty who spoke include Robert Street, Ray Bacchetti, Lowell Price, William Massy, John Ford, John Schwartz, Richard Lyman, Donald Kennedy, and Albert Hastorf. Also includes office files, 1979-1984, containing memoranda, correspondence, articles, class materials, text of talks, and other records.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Phonotapes.; Videorecordings.; Management.; Stanford University. Management Development Program; Price, Lowell W.; Massy, William F.; Hastorf, Albert H.; Kennedy, Donald; Bacchetti, Raymond F.; Stanford University. Personnel Services; Ford, John B.; Street, Robert L.; Lyman, Richard W.; Schwartz, John J.
- Audiovisual Materials, Accession ACCN-1994-024
  - Stanford Management Development Program, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Management Development Program, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - MDP Papers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brown University (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SC - Needs Assessment (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Papers (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ray Bacchetti: Oct. 5, 1979 [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mayhew: Oct. 5, 1979 [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Munter: Oct. 5, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B. Rosenzweig: Oct. 19, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - J. Smith: Oct. 26, 1979 [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - J. Kouzes: Nov. 2, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Graham: Nov. 9, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Implementation Neg. 1978-1980 [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - D. Kennedy: Nov. 16, 1979 [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Open Session: Nov. 30, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - B. Massy: Dec. 7, 1979 [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - J. Adams: Dec. 14, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ray, Kent, Nancy: Jan. 11, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Creighton, Wheeler, Katchadourian: Jan. 25, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Pres. Lyman: Feb. 1, 1980 [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Leavitt: Feb. 8, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - A. Hasdorf: Feb. 23, 1980 [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Panel: Feb. 29, 1980 [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Trustees: March 7, 1980 [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Students: March 14, 1980 [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - R. Parker: March 21, 1980 [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Learning Contract (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Practicum Mtgs. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - MDP Notes: 1980-81 (1) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - MDP Notes: 1980-81 (2) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - MDP Notes (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Quarterly Mtg. 2/15/84 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Implementation (10/25/83) - Zirpolo (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Supton, Brandt, Benson (11/1/83) - [1 Cassette: Box 8] (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Special Session w/ Al Hastorf (11/8/83) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Managing Financial Resources (2/14/84), Riggs, Hinchliffe, Ford [2 cassettes: Box 9] (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Participant-Created Session (1/31/84) [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Managing Financial Resources: Budgeting (1/24/84) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Special Session with Faculty (2/7/84) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Analysis, Problem Formulation, & Judgement.. ., (1/10/84) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Managing Financial Resources: Introduction (1/17/84), Massy [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Managing Financial Resources: Investments (2/21/84), Adams [1 cassette: Box 8] (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Managing Technology (2/28/84), Shaw [2 cassettes: Box 8] (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Issues in Legal Affairs (3/6/84), Schwartz (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Participant-Created Session (3/13/84) [1 cassette: Box 9] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ethics in Management (3/20/84), Hanson (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures and Seminars (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Problem Identification, Analysis & Judgement (1/19/82), Bacchetti (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Early Decision Making (1/26/82), Beyers (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Human Resources Management: Managerial Philosophy (2/23/82),Hansen (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Legal Issues (3/16/?), Schwartz (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Power and Social Influence (11/24/81), Miller (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Budgeting (12/14/82), Peterson... (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising (1/25/83), Hinchliffe (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Managing Financial Resources (1/11/83), Massy (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Special Session (Students), 4/5/83 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Human Resources Principles (11/16/82), Parker (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Consultation & Negotiation (10/19/82), Miner... (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Problem Identification, Analysis & Judgement (10/12/82), Bacchetti (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Curriculum (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Consultation and Negotiation (12/8/81), Miner (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Leadership and Governance at Stanford (11/10/?), Hutchinson (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Human Resources Management: Introduction (11/3/81), Parker (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Special Session with Students (4/13/82) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Open Session I (1/4/83) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Budget Process (10/20/81), Peterson (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Management of Complexity: Ethics (3/1/83), Williams (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stanford's External Environment (3/8/83), Freelen (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Open Session II (3/29/83) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Human Resources Practices (11/30/82), Hansen (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Interaction with the External Environment: Development (11/17/81), Hinchliffe (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lunch - 8/30/83 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Retreat (10/6-7/83) [2 cassettes: Box 9]. These two cassettes belong to one entry only: 1983 or 1984. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Consultation (10/18/83), Price (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Making Effective Presentations (1/15/83), Bower (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Managing Human Resources (11/22/83), Parker [1 cassette: Box 9] (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Managing Human Resources, continued (11/29/83), Parker [2 cassettes: Box 9] (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Participant Created Session (12/6/83) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - University Governance (12/13/83), Peterson [2 cassettes: Box 9] (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Participant Created Session (3/27/84) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Issues in Medical Affairs (4/3/84), Crowley [2 cassettes: Box 9] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Special Session with Students (4/10/84) [1 cassette: Box 9] (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Issues in External Relations (4/17/84), Freelen [2 cassettes: Box 9] (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Special Session (5/1/84), Kennedy (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Retreat (5/31/84) [2 cassettes: Box 9]. These two cassettes belong to one entry only: 1983 or 1984. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lecture (6/7/84) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Adjunct Activity: Computer Concepts (7/27/84) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Audio Cassettes
    - Audiocassettes (Box 8-9)
    - October 14: Organizational Structure (Scott), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - October 21: Planning Models for Colleges and Universities (Hopkins), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - October 28: Stanford's Budget Process (Bacchetti/Peterson), 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - November 11: Management, Leadership, and Governance at Stanford including the Role of the Board of Trustees (Hamrdla), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - November 25: Interaction with the External Environment: Public Affairs and Government Relations (Rosenzweig/Freelen), 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - December 2: Interaction with the External Environment: Development (Smith), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - December 9: Stanford's Internal Social Influence Process: Communications Skills (Packer), 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - December 16: Stanford's Internal Social Influence Process: Consultation and Negotiation Skills (Miner/Horton/Wheeler), 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - January 20: Ethics of Decision Making (Rosenzweig/Freelen/ Yearley), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - February 3: Phases of the Problem-Solving Process: Analysis and Judgement (Generating Solutions) (Bacchetti), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
    - February 17: Mechanism for Decision-Making: Legal Issues and the Role of the Law (Schwartz), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - February 24: Mechanism for Decision-Making: Accounting (Horngren/Riddle), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - March 3: Mechanism for Decision-Making: Fianance (Massy), 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - March 10: Mechanism for Decision-Making: Information Systems in Computing (Shaw), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - March 17: Characteristics of Ineffective Groups -- What to Avoid (Porras/Roberts), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - March 24: Characteristics of Highly Effective Groups -- Structure, Roles, Process, Norms (Porras/Roberts), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - March 31: Special Session with the President, 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - April 7: The Manager as a Person (Kaplan/Marchick/Thomas), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    - April 14: Philosophy of Management (McPherson), 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 12)
    - April 21: Management Styles, Thinking Styles, Learning Styles (Engel), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 12)
    - April 28: Personnel Administration (Parker), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous:
    - E. Shaw, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 12)
    - Desert Survival: Group A (Parker), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 12)
  - "Orientation for Stanford Supervisors: Management Development Program 1981-1982", 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 13)